<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>

<!--
The following information is taken from https://www.goodreads.com/
Book genres are taken from https://www.wikipedia.org/
-->
<books>

    <book>
        <id>1</id>
        <title>1984</title>
        <author>George Orwell</author>
        <publisher>Hughton Mifflin Harcourt</publisher>
        <publishingYear>2013</publishingYear>
        <genre>dystopian</genre>
        <numberOfPages>237</numberOfPages>
        <description>Among the seminal texts of the 20th century, Nineteen Eighty-Four is a rare work that grows more haunting as its futuristic purgatory becomes more real. Published in 1949, the book offers political satirist George Orwell's nightmare vision of a totalitarian, bureaucratic world and one poor stiff's attempt to find individuality. The brilliance of the novel is Orwell's prescience of modern life--the ubiquity of television, the distortion of the language--and his ability to construct such a thorough version of hell. Required reading for students since it was published, it ranks among the most terrifying novels ever written.</description>
        <url>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40961427-1984</url>
        <imageUrl>https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1532714506l/40961427.jpg</imageUrl>
        <available>true</available>
    </book>

    <book>
        <id>2</id>
        <title>The Catcher in the Rye</title>
        <author>J.D. Salinger</author>
        <publisher>Back Bay Books</publisher>
        <publishingYear>2001</publishingYear>
        <genre>realistic fiction</genre>
        <numberOfPages>277</numberOfPages>
        <description>The hero-narrator of The Catcher in the Rye is an ancient child of sixteen, a native New Yorker named Holden Caulfield. Through circumstances that tend to preclude adult, secondhand description, he leaves his prep school in Pennsylvania and goes underground in New York City for three days. The boy himself is at once too simple and too complex for us to make any final comment about him or his story. Perhaps the safest thing we can say about Holden is that he was born in the world not just strongly attracted to beauty but, almost, hopelessly impaled on it. There are many voices in this novel: children's voices, adult voices, underground voices-but Holden's voice is the most eloquent of all. Transcending his own vernacular, yet remaining marvelously faithful to it, he issues a perfectly articulated cry of mixed pain and pleasure. However, like most lovers and clowns and poets of the higher orders, he keeps most of the pain to, and for, himself. The pleasure he gives away, or sets aside, with all his heart. It is there for the reader who can handle it to keep.

            J.D. Salinger's classic novel of teenage angst and rebellion was first published in 1951. The novel was included on Time's 2005 list of the 100 best English-language novels written since 1923. It was named by Modern Library and its readers as one of the 100 best English-language novels of the 20th century. It has been frequently challenged in the court for its liberal use of profanity and portrayal of sexuality and in the 1950's and 60's it was the novel that every teenage boy wants to read.</description>
        <url>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/5107.The_Catcher_in_the_Rye</url>
        <imageUrl>https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1398034300l/5107.jpg</imageUrl>
        <available>false</available>
    </book>

    <book>
        <id>3</id>
        <title>Brave New World</title>
        <author>Aldous Huxley</author>
        <publisher>HarperPerennial</publisher>
        <publishingYear>1998</publishingYear>
        <genre>dystopian</genre>
        <numberOfPages>288</numberOfPages>
        <description>Brave New World is a dystopian novel written in 1931 by English author Aldous Huxley, and published in 1932. Largely set in a futuristic World State of genetically modified citizens and an intelligence-based social hierarchy, the novel anticipates huge scientific developments in reproductive technology, sleep-learning, psychological manipulation, and classical conditioning that are combined to make a utopian society that goes challenged only by a single outsider.</description>
        <url>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/5129.Brave_New_World</url>
        <imageUrl>https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1523061131l/5129.jpg</imageUrl>
        <available>false</available>
    </book>

    <book>
        <id>4</id>
        <title>Twilight</title>
        <author>Stephenie Meyer</author>
        <publisher>Little, Brown and Company</publisher>
        <publishingYear>2006</publishingYear>
        <genre>fantasy</genre>
        <numberOfPages>498</numberOfPages>
        <description>In the first book of the Twilight Saga, internationally bestselling author Stephenie Meyer introduces Bella Swan and Edward Cullen, a pair of star-crossed lovers whose forbidden relationship ripens against the backdrop of small-town suspicion and a mysterious coven of vampires. This is a love story with bite.</description>
        <url>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/41865.Twilight</url>
        <imageUrl>https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1361039443l/41865.jpg</imageUrl>
        <available>true</available>
    </book>

    <book>
        <id>5</id>
        <title>Charlotte's Web</title>
        <author>E.B. White</author>
        <publisher>HarperCollinsPublishers</publisher>
        <publishingYear>2001</publishingYear>
        <genre>children</genre>
        <numberOfPages>184</numberOfPages>
        <description>This beloved book by E. B. White, author of Stuart Little and The Trumpet of the Swan, is a classic of children's literature that is "just about perfect." This high-quality paperback features vibrant illustrations colorized by Rosemary Wells!

            Some Pig. Humble. Radiant. These are the words in Charlotte's Web, high up in Zuckerman's barn. Charlotte's spiderweb tells of her feelings for a little pig named Wilbur, who simply wants a friend. They also express the love of a girl named Fern, who saved Wilbur's life when he was born the runt of his litter.

            E. B. White's Newbery Honor Book is a tender novel of friendship, love, life, and death that will continue to be enjoyed by generations to come. This edition contains newly color illustrations by Garth Williams, the acclaimed illustrator of E. B. White's Stuart Little and Laura Ingalls Wilder's Little House series, among many other books.</description>
        <url>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/24178.Charlotte_s_Web</url>
        <imageUrl>https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1439632243l/24178.jpg</imageUrl>
        <available>true</available>
    </book>

    <book>
        <id>6</id>
        <title>Life of Pi</title>
        <author>Yann Martel</author>
        <publisher>Seal Books</publisher>
        <publishingYear>2006</publishingYear>
        <genre>fiction</genre>
        <numberOfPages>460</numberOfPages>
        <description>Life of Pi is a fantasy adventure novel by Yann Martel published in 2001. The protagonist, Piscine Molitor "Pi" Patel, a Tamil boy from Pondicherry, explores issues of spirituality and practicality from an early age. He survives 227 days after a shipwreck while stranded on a boat in the Pacific Ocean with a Bengal tiger named Richard Parker.</description>
        <url>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/4214.Life_of_Pi</url>
        <imageUrl>https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1320562005l/4214.jpg</imageUrl>
        <available>false</available>
    </book>

    <book>
        <id>7</id>
        <title>Harry Potter and the Sorcerer's Stone</title>
        <author>J.K. Rowling</author>
        <publisher>Scholastic Inc</publisher>
        <publishingYear>1997</publishingYear>
        <genre>fantasy</genre>
        <numberOfPages>320</numberOfPages>
        <description>Harry Potter's life is miserable. His parents are dead and he's stuck with his heartless relatives, who force him to live in a tiny closet under the stairs. But his fortune changes when he receives a letter that tells him the truth about himself: he's a wizard. A mysterious visitor rescues him from his relatives and takes him to his new home, Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry.

            After a lifetime of bottling up his magical powers, Harry finally feels like a normal kid. But even within the Wizarding community, he is special. He is the boy who lived: the only person to have ever survived a killing curse inflicted by the evil Lord Voldemort, who launched a brutal takeover of the Wizarding world, only to vanish after failing to kill Harry.

            Though Harry's first year at Hogwarts is the best of his life, not everything is perfect. There is a dangerous secret object hidden within the castle walls, and Harry believes it's his responsibility to prevent it from falling into evil hands. But doing so will bring him into contact with forces more terrifying than he ever could have imagined.

            Full of sympathetic characters, wildly imaginative situations, and countless exciting details, the first installment in the series assembles an unforgettable magical world and sets the stage for many high-stakes adventures to come.</description>
        <url>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/3.Harry_Potter_and_the_Sorcerer_s_Stone</url>
        <imageUrl>https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1474154022l/3.jpg</imageUrl>
        <available>true</available>
    </book>

    <book>
        <id>8</id>
        <title>Animal Farm</title>
        <author>George Orwell</author>
        <publisher>NAL</publisher>
        <publishingYear>2003</publishingYear>
        <genre>political satire</genre>
        <numberOfPages>122</numberOfPages>
        <description>As ferociously fresh as it was more than a half century ago, this remarkable allegory of a downtrodden society of overworked, mistreated animals, and their quest to create a paradise of progress, justice, and equality is one of the most scathing satires ever published. As we witness the rise and bloody fall of the revolutionary animals, we begin to recognize the seeds of totalitarianism in the most idealistic organization; and in our most charismatic leaders, the souls of our cruelest oppressors.</description>
        <url>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/7613.Animal_Farm</url>
        <imageUrl>https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1424037542l/7613.jpg</imageUrl>
        <available>false</available>
    </book>

    <book>
        <id>9</id>
        <title>The Stranger</title>
        <author>Albert Camus</author>
        <publisher>Vintage International</publisher>
        <publishingYear>1989</publishingYear>
        <genre>philosophical</genre>
        <numberOfPages>123</numberOfPages>
        <description>Through the story of an ordinary man unwittingly drawn into a senseless murder on an Algerian beach, Camus explored what he termed "the nakedness of man faced with the absurd." First published in English in 1946; now in a new translation by Matthew Ward.</description>
        <url>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/49552.The_Stranger</url>
        <imageUrl>https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1349927872l/49552.jpg</imageUrl>
        <available>true</available>
    </book>

    <book>
        <id>10</id>
        <title>Bonheur d'occasion</title>
        <author>Gabrielle Roy</author>
        <publisher>Boréal</publisher>
        <publishingYear>2009</publishingYear>
        <genre>novel</genre>
        <numberOfPages>464</numberOfPages>
        <description>Dans le quartier montréalais de Saint-Henri, un peuple d'ouvriers et de petits employés canadiens-français est désespérement en quête de bonheur. Florentine croit avoir trouvé le sien dans l'amour ; Rose-Anna le cherche dans le bien-être de sa famille ; Azarius fuit dans le rêve ; Emmanuel s'enrole ; Jean entreprend son ascension sociale. Chacun, à sa manière, invente sa propre voie de salut et chacun, à sa manière, échoue. Mais leur sort est en même temps celui de million d'autres, non seulement à Montréal mais partout ailleurs, dans un monde en proie à la guerre.</description>
        <url>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/7669164-bonheur-d-occasion</url>
        <imageUrl>https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1313504255l/7669164.jpg</imageUrl>
        <available>true</available>
    </book>

    <book>
        <id>11</id>
        <title>Mastery</title>
        <author>Robert Greene</author>
        <publisher>Viking</publisher>
        <publishingYear>2012</publishingYear>
        <genre>non-fiction</genre>
        <numberOfPages>318</numberOfPages>
        <description>Mastery synthesizes the years of research Robert Greene conducted while writing the international bestsellers The 48 Laws of Power, The 33 Strategies of War, and The Art of Seduction and demonstrates that the ultimate form of power is mastery itself. By analyzing the lives of such past masters as Charles Darwin, Benjamin Franklin, Albert Einstein, and Leonard da Vinci, as well as by interviewing nine contemporary masters, including tech guru Paul Graham and animal rights advocate Temple Grandin, Greene debunks our culture’s many myths about genius and distills the wisdom of the ages to reveal the secret to greatness. With this seminal text as a guide, readers will learn how to unlock the passion within and become masters.</description>
        <url>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13589182-mastery</url>
        <imageUrl>https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1348274726l/13589182.jpg</imageUrl>
        <available>true</available>
    </book>

    <book>
        <id>12</id>
        <title>The Great Gatsby</title>
        <author>F. Scott Fitzgerald</author>
        <publisher>Scribner</publisher>
        <publishingYear>2004</publishingYear>
        <genre>novel</genre>
        <numberOfPages>180</numberOfPages>
        <description>A true classic of twentieth-century literature, this edition has been updated by Fitzgerald scholar James L.W. West III to include the author’s final revisions and features a note on the composition and text, a personal foreword by Fitzgerald’s granddaughter, Eleanor Lanahan—and a new introduction by two-time National Book Award winner Jesmyn Ward.

            The Great Gatsby, F. Scott Fitzgerald’s third book, stands as the supreme achievement of his career. First published in 1925, this quintessential novel of the Jazz Age has been acclaimed by generations of readers. The story of the mysteriously wealthy Jay Gatsby and his love for the beautiful Daisy Buchanan, of lavish parties on Long Island at a time when The New York Times noted “gin was the national drink and sex the national obsession,” it is an exquisitely crafted tale of America in the 1920s.</description>
        <url>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/4671.The_Great_Gatsby</url>
        <imageUrl>https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1490528560l/4671.jpg</imageUrl>
        <available>false</available>
    </book>

    <book>
        <id>13</id>
        <title>The Origin of Species</title>
        <author>Charles Darwin</author>
        <publisher>Castle Books</publisher>
        <publishingYear>2004</publishingYear>
        <genre>scientific literature</genre>
        <numberOfPages>703</numberOfPages>
        <description>Darwin's theory of natural selection issued a profound challenge to orthodox thought and belief: no being or species has been specifically created; all are locked into a pitiless struggle for existence, with extinction looming for those not fitted for the task.

            Yet The Origin of Species (1859) is also a humane and inspirational vision of ecological interrelatedness, revealing the complex mutual interdependencies between animal and plant life, climate and physical environment, and - by implication - within the human world.

            Written for the general reader, in a style which combines the rigour of science with the subtlety of literature, The Origin of Species remains one of the founding documents of the modern age.</description>
        <url>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/22463.The_Origin_of_Species</url>
        <imageUrl>https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1298417570l/22463.jpg</imageUrl>
        <available>true</available>
    </book>

    <book>
        <id>14</id>
        <title>For Whom the Bell Tolls</title>
        <author>Ernest Hemingway</author>
        <publisher>Scribner</publisher>
        <publishingYear>1995</publishingYear>
        <genre>war</genre>
        <numberOfPages>471</numberOfPages>
        <description>In 1937 Ernest Hemingway traveled to Spain to cover the civil war there for the North American Newspaper Alliance. Three years later he completed the greatest novel to emerge from "the good fight", For Whom the Bell Tolls.

            The story of Robert Jordan, a young American in the International Brigades attached to an antifascist guerilla unit in the mountains of Spain, it tells of loyalty and courage, love and defeat, and the tragic death of an ideal. In his portrayal of Jordan's love for the beautiful Maria and his superb account of El Sordo's last stand, in his brilliant travesty of La Pasionaria and his unwillingness to believe in blind faith, Hemingway surpasses his achievement in The Sun Also Rises and A Farewell to Arms to create a work at once rare and beautiful, strong and brutal, compassionate, moving and wise.

            "If the function of a writer is to reveal reality," Maxwell Perkins wrote to Hemingway after reading the manuscript, "no one ever so completely performed it." Greater in power, broader in scope, and more intensely emotional than any of the author's previous works, it stands as one of the best war novels of all time.</description>
        <url>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/46170.For_Whom_the_Bell_Tolls</url>
        <imageUrl>https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1492591524l/46170.jpg</imageUrl>
        <available>false</available>
    </book>

    <book>
        <id>15</id>
        <title>The Old Man and the Sea</title>
        <author>Ernest Hemingway</author>
        <publisher>Scribner</publisher>
        <publishingYear>1996</publishingYear>
        <genre>literary fiction</genre>
        <numberOfPages>132</numberOfPages>
        <description>It is the story of an old Cuban fisherman and his supreme ordeal: a relentless, agonizing battle with a giant marlin far out in the Gulf Stream. Using the simple, powerful language of a fable, Hemingway takes the timeless themes of courage in the face of defeat and personal triumph won from loss and transforms them into a magnificent twentieth-century classic.</description>
        <url>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/2165.The_Old_Man_and_the_Sea</url>
        <imageUrl>https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1329189714l/2165.jpg</imageUrl>
        <available>true</available>
    </book>

</books>